Today I have a simpler video for you.
今天我来给大家讲点简单的
Simple? On this channel? Sounds unpossible.
嘛玩意？这频道还有简单视频？你没拿我找乐吧
I know right! But really it’s pretty simple!
我知道！但是这个视频真的很通俗易懂
Yeah right, let’s just take a quick peek at …
是啊，要不咱看看......
oh.
好吧:-P
Author: If you're on mobile it says 9:32 because who cares about consistency across the platform?
作者淘气：要是播放器的话，那就是9:32，因为谁会管跨平台的一致性呢？
I guess it is pretty simple.
也许这个视频真的很简单
Yep, told ya so!
是啊，早就跟你说了
I am in fact capable of making shorter videos.
实际上我能做短视频
Well, this gag sure isn’t helping with that.
行了吧，你说了也没用
Indeed. so let’s introduce the topic and talk about these little cassette adapter thingies.
好吧，那我们少说废话，来谈下磁带转换器吧
注：淘宝售价9元左右
If you have an older car which only has a cassette deck but you need your sweet AUX JACK,
如果你有一辆只有磁带卡座的老爷车，而你需要用亲切的音频插座的话
well, you’ll probably have used one of these before.
那么你一定会用过这个
And they’ve been around for quite a while.
而且这玩意已经在世很多年了
Back when a CD Walkman was the height of sophistication,
早在CD Walkman十分成熟的时候
you could modernize your car with one of these
你会在你的车上装上这个"现代化"的玩意
and be enjoying the best the world of Compact Disc has to offer.
然后享受CD带来的美妙音质
Ever wonder how they work?
你们有想过它们是怎么工作的吗
Only all the time!
是啊，你可倒是说啊
No! Stop. That gag is over.
嘿，说你呢！再说的话，出去！
To understand how this works, we first need to understand a bit about the technology behind audio tape.
为了了解它的原理，我们需要些磁带背后的原理
Fricken’ tapes. How do they work?
这没人要的外语磁带到底是怎么发出声音的？
Magnets!
那自然是————磁力！
Magnetic tape is some pretty neat stuff, though it’s not groovy I’ll tell you that.
磁带是个好玩意，当然现在说有点落款
Instead it’s particular.
实际上这个还挺特别的
Conventional type I audio tape is simply a thin ribbon of plastic backing which has a
一般的一类磁带基本上就是一层很薄的塑料
bunch of finely ground-up rust smeared all over it.
上面铺满了一层铁锈（实际上是四氧化三铁）
The iron oxide particles can be magnetized with a little help from an electromagnet.
这些氧化铁粒子可以通过电磁铁给磁化
Inside a cassette deck (or really any tape deck at all), a special electromagnet called
在卡座里（不管是什么磁带的），一块称作
the head makes contact with the tape as it travels past it.
磁头的特制电磁铁会与通过的磁带接触
Fun fact!
还挺好玩的哈！
注：不知道现在初中物理课本STS环节还有这个吗？
In video tape, the heads do the traveling!
在视频磁带中，磁头是会动的！
I made a video waaaaay long ago about that if you’re interested.
你感兴趣的话，我老久之前做了一个视频
Now, because the tape is made of fine particles, different spots along its length can be magnetized
那么，鉴于磁带上面铺满了细小的铁颗粒，这条磁带的各个部分都可以
to different extents.
被磁化为不同磁性
Think of it like a bunch of teeny tiny bits of metal that can more or less be individually magnetized.
想象一下，一堆十分细小的铁颗粒可以分别给磁化
If you move this granular tape across the head as it gets all electromagnety,
如果你将这些有磁性颗粒的带子与电磁铁摩擦的话
you will end up with a linear representation of how intense the magnetic field the head created
你最终将会得到一个线状的、清晰分明的、
was over time.
由磁头一直画出来的磁场分布图
Spots that were exposed to a strong field will be strongly magnetized, and spots that
暴露在超强磁场的部分会被磁化
weren’t exposed will be hardly magnetized at all.
未被暴露在磁场的部分就基本没被磁化
Tie that magnetization level to some sort of signal, like perhaps audio,
而这种磁性变化就可以承载信息了，比如声音
and you will end up with that signal represented on the tape.
然后你就可以在磁带上录音了
Check out this neat video from Techmoan if you want to see what that signal actually looks like.
如果你对信号的模样感兴趣的话，你可以看看Techmoan的这个视频
注：3M制造的磁带磁性查看器：av99685974
The thing about electromagnets though is that they work backwards, too!
这个电磁铁不仅可以磁化磁带，还可以读取磁带
When a pre-recorded tape, complete with signals already on it, is run past the same head,
当提前录制好的磁带经过电磁铁的话的话，
the head can detect the signal!
磁头便可以侦测到信号啦
The changes in the magnetic field the head encounters as the magnetized tape travels
磁头侦测到磁带的磁性变化会
注：请各位打开物理选修3-2，复习楞次定律，练习右手螺旋定则
past it induces a small current in its tiny little coils.
变成磁头线圈的微小电流
Even though it’s just a bunch of tiny magnetized particles, it has the same effect as moving
尽管各个小磁铁很微小，当它们
a magnet past a coil of wire and will thus induce a current in that coil.
一起经过磁头时，它们形成的磁场会加强线圈的电流
This can be amplified to recreate the original signal, and thus sound,
这个电流可以放大，以产生原始信号
that was imparted on the tape when it was recorded.
那么声音也就是这么从磁带忠实地还原了
But of course, these adapters don’t have any tape in them.
但连派大星都知道，这些转接器里面都没有磁带呀
Wait, do they? No. No they don’t.
等会，真没有吗？嗯，是没有:-|
So what do they have?
那么这里面有什么名堂呢？
Well, for a start, an absurd number of incongruous logos that don’t belong anywhere near this thing.
你来看看这上面这堆和磁带八杆子打不着的玩意
Like, these are hilarious.
看看这堆搞笑的东西
Compact Disc? MiniDisc?
光盘？MiniDisc？
Pfft.
:-P
I like that the DCC logo is on here because you could kind of argue that it is a digital
我喜欢这上面的DCC（数码磁带）标志，因为这好歹能让你想到
compact cassette so long as it’s plugged into like a CD player or whatever.
磁带之类的东西，只要将其与CD播放器之类的东西相连接
Anyway, first consider what this does.
无论如何，咱先看看这个要干什么
It needs to produce the same effect as a real tape - so it needs to induce a current based
这个要模拟磁带的作用的话，就要由卡座的磁头侦测到
on an audio signal in the playback head of whatever cassette player you’re using it in, but without actual tape.
音频磁信号并转换为电流，但这回不是磁带产生音频磁信号
How could you go about doing that?
那这个是怎么做到的？
Well, remember that it’s the same head in most cassette decks that does the recording as the playing back.
请大家注意，大多数卡座都由一个磁头来录制和播放
The same head can be used as an electromagnet to record onto a tape or as a pickup coil
同样的磁头可以当电磁铁，用来向磁带录音或
(or magnetic microphone if you will) to play a tape back.
用作拾音线圈（或称电磁麦克风）用来播放磁带
And so, take a look at where the tape should be and you’ll find a tape head!
那么，咱来看看磁带本应在的位置呢，你会发现一个磁头！
A cassette adaptor like this uses a tape head just like the one in your cassette player,
像这样的磁带转换器都会用和磁带播放器一样的磁头
and when it’s loaded in a cassette deck the two heads get real personal with one another.
在适配器装入卡座里后，这两个磁头会互相接触
The signal coming from the audio jack is pumped into that head, which is essentially coupled
从插口传过来的声音信号就会传入卡座磁头，这俩信号是
with the other, and the end result is that the audio signal from your phone, iPod, or whatever
相吻合的，最终从你电话，随身听之类传入的信号
is injected right into the other head and thus into amplification circuitry
会被传入另一个磁头，进而传入卡座的
of the cassette deck so it can play through your ‘96 Civic’s stereo or whatever.
放大电路，然后声音就可以从你的老爷车音箱中放出了
注：原文Civic是1996年Honda生产的车
It’s that simple!
就是如此简单
Ah, but it’s not quite *so* simple.
额，但是这也没那么简单:-|
You see, many cassette decks have some sort of auto stop feature which works by detecting
你瞧，很多磁带卡座都有通过侦测转轮是否旋转的
that the supply spool has stopped.
自动停止装置
Since there’s no actual tape in here at all, the supply spool wouldn’t turn on its own
鉴于转换器内没有真正的磁带，转轮不会自己转起来
and the tape player would just… repeatedly stop, thinking it had reached the end of the tape.
磁带播放机就会一直认为磁带已经放完
So, these usually contain a mechanism to cause the supply spool to turn with the take-up spool
所以，这些转换器自己还有一个机制来带动转轮
(the latter of which is turned by the cassette player itself)
（转轮本身是由磁带转动的）
to prevent this from happening.
以防止上述情况的发生
Some models will also prevent the reels from turning backwards, forcing an auto-reverse
有些型号还会阻止滚轮向反方向滚动，
deck into the forward position and ensuring the playback heads align with the little
让磁带走带装置一直向一个方向走，保证回放时拾音头与
broadcast heads, if you will, of the adapter.
转换器的头相对齐
And is it really so simple as a playback head wired to an audio jack?
还有，难道这转换头和音频接口就接着一根线吗？
Wouldn’t there need to be some sort of circuit in there to make the signal from the audio jack work?
难道不需要某种电路来让音频接口传来的信号工作？
Well, let’s find out by taking this apart.
来吧，一拆见真知:-)
It turns out that yep.
嗯，咱想的没错
It literally is that simple.
就是这么简单
Just the wires from the jack going right to the head.
把插头传入的信号都给泵入转换头
Now, this head might be designed specifically for this purpose, though I kinda doubt it,
当然，这个头也许就是为了这个目的设计的，然而我很怀疑
but I suppose it is possible.
但是这也许是真的呢
Since the same head can record and play on a typical cassette deck,
既然这个头既可以在卡座里用来录制和播放
could this be used in reverse?
那么这个可以将卡座信号传给转换器吗？
What if I plugged this into an audio recorder, and hit record on this guy and fed a signal into it?
要是我把这个插进录音机，然后在卡座上向转换器输入信号的话
Would it be detectable by the audio recorder?
这信号会被录音机侦测到吗？
Turns out, yes!
实验结果是......可以！
Since the tape bias signal is well outside the audible range
虽然磁带机的信号小到听不见
it doesn’t seem to affect things too much and you do in fact get a signal
但这对实验结果没有影响，这确实能将
out of the cassette adapter. [tinny music is heard]
信号传入磁带转换器[尽管声音超小:-(]
While this is completely and totally useless, it is at least mildly interesting.
尽管这个超级没用，但这个还是有点意思的
You might be surprised at the audio fidelity these things are capable of when used in the more normal fashion.
你会发现，就算按照现在的标准，这玩意的音质也是很不错的
For one thing, there is no tape noise at all when you use these.
比如说，这玩意没有磁带的谜之底噪
That hiss you hear from a tape is a result of the random structure of the magnetic particles themselves.
而这堆噪音一般是由磁带上磁性粒子的不同造成的
You can’t get rid of it unless you use some clever tricks like Dolby Noise Reduction,
你不能去掉它，除非你用些特殊技巧，诸如杜比降噪
and even then it will still always be there a little bit.
而且就算开了，也是还有一点:-P
But if you don’t have any tape, well there’s no tape noise!
但是你要是不用磁带的话，磁带底噪就没了
Seriously, to my ears using one of these, even a really terrible one like this, is basically
说真的，对我而言，就算是用这个超级垃圾的转换器，
indistinguishable from a legitimate auxiliary input.
我也基本没法和有线输入的区分开
It’s pretty remarkable.
这个挺好
Oh and by the way, if you use these you want to make sure Dolby noise reduction is turned
顺便说一句，你要用这个的话，你得关掉杜比降噪
off as otherwise you’re getting a needless reduction in fidelity in the form of a rather
要不然的话你就得到了一个有损音质
pronounced treble cut.
高频信号都给切了
And of course, for one last fun tidbit, since electronics keep getting smaller and cheaper
最后来点好玩的花絮，因为目前电器部件越来越小
we now have Bluetooth versions of these!
我们现在有适配蓝牙功能的了
These are actually really neat, they have a small battery with a micro USB port to recharge it,
这个东西很小，里面有块电池，通过微型USB接口充电
and a module inside allows you to pair your phone with it so you can play music through
里面还有蓝牙模块和手机适配，然后你就可以在这个适配器的帮助下
its little integrated head.
播放音乐了
They even give you a little microphone on a dongle for making hands-free calls.
这个里面甚至还有装着话筒，用来免提通话
I have no idea how well that part of it works but for $15 this thing is pretty neat.
我不知道这个的原理，但是这个玩意90块钱（15美元）也还行
I remember seeing in the past that someone had put out an MP3 player inside one of these
我记得当年有人在这里面装个MP3
cassette shells complete with transport control buttons and its own headphone jack,
还有控制按钮和音频接口
giving you hipster cred when you needed it and actually being useful in older cars.
当时用在老爷车上就显得潮:-|
I tried looking for it again but “cassette MP3 adapter” is a woefully unspecific term these days so…
我在网上又找了一遍，但是“磁带MP3适配器”就是找不到......
well it’s probably still a thing but personally these Bluetooth ones which you can find in stores now
也许这个还会存在，但是现在咱们所找到的蓝牙适配器
would be my preference as they’re actually quite capable of modernizing an otherwise old car.
真的在老爷车上面用十分合适
Well, that’s it! Can you believe it? A reasonably short video from Technology Connections!
好的，咱就这样？我真没想到咱频道也做了这个超级短的视频！
I feel like I must be dreaming.
我敢说我一定是在做梦
Anyway, time to leave you with everyone’s favorite smooth jazz hit.
无论如何，我该用这个喜闻乐见的放松爵士乐来结束本期节目了
I… I can’t find the boombox I wanted for this shot so you know,
我找不到为这个节目准备的音响了
just pretend.
咱凑合一下
It’s kinda loud.
还挺吵的呢
以下是花絮部分
...but you need your sweet, sweet aux jack…
但是你得需要用你最喜欢的音频接口......
mm … that didn’t go well.
嗯，语气不对:-(
Conventional type I audio tape, which this is not, is simply a thin ribbon of plastic
普通的一类磁带，当然这个不是，就是在一层薄塑料上......
… yeah I should get a type I tape.
不行，必须得拿一个一类带
Shouldn’t I?
我必须得拿吗?
We can’t…. we can’t use this chrome tape because you pedants would be like
我不能用这个二类带，要不总有人会钻牛角尖
“that’s a Maxell XLII! That’s not type I tape!”
“这个是Maxell XL 二类带！才不是啥一类带！”
so, gotta change it!
所以呢，咱必须得换!
...and talk about these little cassette adapter thingies…
......然后咱谈一下这个磁带转换器......
hoo that was a bad…
感觉不对
My nose itched. Probably a fine take.
刚才鼻子难受，兴许一会就好了
...range it doesn't’ seem to affect things too much and you do in fact get a signal this is really rattly
......听不见，但是这对实验结果没有影响，而且这确实能咯咯地......
That magnetization level to some so…
那么磁性变化就可以......
Aagh!
啊！
Tie!
That was the word, tie!
怎么会是这个词？Tie!
I was like “tie? That doesn't make any sense!”
我当时想：“Tie? 放着根本不合适!”
No, you wrote that word.
唉，自己写台本自己受累吧:-P
Author: I cannot tell you how relieved I was that the video actually shows as 9:31 long here in the player.
作者淘气：当我看见这个视频在播放器里显示为9:31长时，我有多释然
本视频由SuperBart翻译，原作者 Technology Connections 发布于2020年7月13日
BUT ONLY ON DESKTOP! In the video manager, mobile, (and probably on the home screen) it says it's 9:32.
但是只在电脑上显示这个！在视频管理器，手机（兴许还有电视）上显示为9:32
So you just can't win.
所以你说服不了我
Anyway bye.
无论如何，下期再见！